Guide to the Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Papers, 1936-2015
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES II. WRITINGS
  - Articles
    - L'Invenzione della Stampa, 1981-1982 (Folder 12.8)
    - The Libraire-Philosophe: Four Sketches for a Group Portrait, 1995-1996 (Folder 12.9)
    - The Libraire-Philosophe: Four Sketches for a Group Portrait, 1997 (Folder 12.10)
    - Of Making Many Books, circa 2012 (Folder 12.11)
    - On the Failure of Scholars to Preach What They Practice, circa 1965 (Folder 12.12)
    - On Revolution and the Printed Word, 1982-1985 (Folder 70.5)
    - On Revolution and the Printed Word, circa 1983 (Folders 12.13-14)
    - On Revolution and the Printed Word, circa 1985-1986 (Folder 13.1)
    - On Solving Our Common Culture Problem, 1963 (Folder 70.6)
    - Print Culture, circa 2006-2009 (Folder 13.2)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, 1985-1986 (Folders 13.3-4)
    - Printing, 1986 (Folder 13.5)
    - Printing, 2009 (Folder 13.6)
    - Printing: Cultural Impact, 1982-1987 (Folder 13.7)
    - The Publicist and the Demagogue, circa 1989 (Folder 13.8)
    - Rapid Change in Retrospect: Comments on the Recent Acceleration of History Book Time, 1964 (Folder 13.9)
    - Rapid Change in Retrospect: Comments on the Recent Acceleration of History Book Time, 1964-1965 (Folder 13.10)
    - A Reply, 1967 (Folder 13.11)
    - Seeing Images and Hearing Texts, circa 2008 (Folder 13.12)
    - Some Conjectures about the Impact of Printing on Western Society and Thought, 1968 (Folder 14.1)
    - Some Conjectures about the Impact of Printing on Western Society and Thought, 1965-1971; [correspondence relating to] (Folder 14.2)
    - The Tribune of the People: a New Species of Demagogue, circa 1991 (Folders 14.3-5)
    - An Unacknowledged Revolution Revisited, 2000; [old version] (Folder 14.6)
    - An Unacknowledged Revolution Revisited, 2001-2002 (Folders 14.7-9)
    - Who Intervened in 1788?, circa 1965 (Folder 14.10)
    - Who Intervened in 1788?, 1965-1971; [correspondence relating to] (Folder 14.11)
    - Assorted articles, circa 1981-circa 1986 (Folder 14.12)
  - Books
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, circa 2008-2011 (Folder 15.1)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, 2009-2010; [correspondence relating to] (Folder 15.2)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, circa 2010-2011; [images] (Folders 15.3-7)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, circa 2006-circa 2009; [notes and clippings] (Folder 15.8)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, 2005-2011; [publicity] (Folder 15.9)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, 2009; [readers' reports] (Folder 15.10)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, circa 2001-circa 2007; [research materials] (Folder 15.11)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, 2012-2013; [reviews] (Folder 15.12)
    - Divine Art, Infernal Machine, circa 2010; [summary] (Folder 15.13)
    - The First Professional Revolutionist: Filippo Michele Buonarroti, 1952-1976 (Folder 15.14)
    - Grub Street Abroad, circa 1993; [images] (Folder 15.15)
    - Grub Street Abroad, undated; [notes] (Folder 15.16)
    - Grub Street Abroad, 1993-1996; [reviews] (Folder 15.17)
    - Printers and Publicists in the Age of the Hand Press, 1993; [proposal for essay collection] (Folder 16.1)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, circa 1979; [outlines] (Folder 70.7)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1987; [papers in response to] (Folder 16.2)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1979-1982; [reviews A-F] (Folder 16.3)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1979-1982; [reviews G-K] (Folder 16.4)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1979-1982; [reviews L-Y] (Folder 70.8)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1993; [review] (Folder 16.5)
    - The Printing Press as an Agent of Change, 1979-1982; [reviews: duplicates and short reviews] (Folder 70.9)
    - The Printing Revolution in Early Modern Europe, circa 2003 (Folders 16.6-8)
    - The Printing Revolution in Early Modern Europe, 2003; [proofs] (Folders 16.9-11)
    - Rapid Change in Retrospect: Essays and Debates, circa 2011-circa 2013 (Folder 17.1)
  - Book Reviews
    - Books and Sciences in History, 2001 (Folder 17.2)
    - The Cambridge History of the Book in Britain, III, 2001 (Folder 17.3)
    - The Cultural Uses of Print in Early Modern France, circa 1988 (Folder 17.4)
    - The Democratic Movement Under the Directory, 1971 (Folder 17.5)
    - Essays on Manuscripts and Rare Books, 1976 (Folder 17.6)
    - Essays on the Heritage of the Renaissance from Homer to Gutenberg, 1983-1984 (Folder 17.7)
    - The Evolution of the Book, 1998 (Folder 17.8)
    - Five Hundred Years of Printing, 1997-1999 (Folder 17.9)
    - France and North America, 1976 (Folder 17.10)
    - La France et la Hongrie au debut de XVIIIe siecle, 1973 (Folder 17.11)
    - The Future of the Book, 1996-1997 (Folder 17.12)
    - Les Almanachs populaires aux XVIIe et XVIIIe siecles, 1971 (Folder 17.13)
    - L'Histoire Sociale, 1967 (Folder 17.14)
    - In the Public Eye: a History of Reading in Modern France, 1800-1940, 1991-1992 (Folder 17.15)
    - The Marketplace of Print, 1998-1999 (Folder 17.16)
    - Massimo d'Azeglio: an Artist in Politics, 1967 (Folder 17.17)
    - Press and Politics in Pre-Revolutionary France, circa 1988 (Folder 17.18)
    - Print, Manuscript and the Search for Order, circa 2004 (Folder 17.19)
    - Print, Power, and People in Seventeenth Century France, 1994-1995 (Folder 17.20)
    - Printing and the Written Word/Printing, Propaganda, Martin Luther, 1992-1996 (Folder 17.21)
    - Le Reforme et le livre, 1990-1991 (Folder 17.22)
    - Revolutionary France, 1770-1880, 1993-1994 (Folder 17.23)
    - Roland de la Platiere, 1967 (Folder 17.24)
    - Miscellaneous book reviews, circa 1971-circa 2001 (Folder 17.25)
  - Lectures
    - Adventures on the Senior Tennis Circuit, 2007 (Folder 17.26)
    - Another Look at L'Ancien Regime Typographique, circa 1980 (Folder 17.27)
    - Boston talk, 2006 (Folder 17.28)
    - Calgary talks, 1999 (Folder 18.1)
    - The Cathedral and the Book, circa 2010 (Folder 18.2)
    - Celebrating Western Technology in the Age of the Hand Press, 1992 (Folder 18.3)
    - Celebrating Western Technology in the Age of the Hand Press, 2004-2005 (Folder 18.4)
    - Columbus and Gutenberg, 2003 (Folder 18.5)
    - Corcoran lecture, 2010 (Folder 18.6)
    - Curti lectures 2 and 3, 1992-2001 (Folder 18.7)
    - Curti lecture additions, circa 2001 (Folder 18.8)
    - Curtis Lecture - Vassar College, 2013-2014 (Folder 18.9)
    - The Debut of the French Publicist in Politics, undated (Folder 18.10)
    - Divine Art: Celebrating Western Technology, 1993 (Folder 18.11)
    - Divine Art: Celebrating Western Technology, 1993-1997 (Folder 19.1)
    - Divine Art/Infernal Maching: the 18th Century Confronts the Printing Press, 1996 (Folder 19.2)
    - Divine Art/Infernal Maching: Western Views of Printing from Gutenberg to McLuhan, 1992 (Folder 19.3)
    - The Early Printer as "Renaissance Man,", circa 1980 (Folder 19.4)
    - Encounters with the Printed Text in the Age of Incunabula, 1996 (Folder 19.5)
    - Encyclopedias in Historical Perspective, 1993 (Folder 19.6)
    - Encyclopedias in Historical Perspective, 1993 (Folder 70.10)
    - The Expansion of the Republic of Letters and the Rejection of the Ancien regime, circa 1970 (Folder 70.11)
    - The Expansion of the Republic of Letters and the Rejection of the Ancien regime, 1970-1971 (Folders 71.1-2)
    - Extra talks, undated (Folder 19.7)
    - The Fifteenth Century Media Revolution, 1993 (Folder 19.8)
    - The Fifteenth Century Media Revolution, circa 1999 (Folder 19.9)
    - From a Divine Art to the Printing Machine and Beyond, 2011-2012 (Folder 19.10)
    - From Printed Word to Moving Image, 1997 (Folder 19.11)
    - From Scriptoria to Printing Shops, 1980-1981 (Folder 19.12)
    - Georgetown Library talk, 2011 (Folder 19.13)
    - Gods, Devils, and Gutenberg, 1996 (Folder 19.14)
    - Grub Street Abroad, 1991 (Folder 20.1)
    - The History of the Book and the History of Ideas, 1984 (Folder 20.2)
    - Ideas of Progress, circa 2001 (Folder 20.3)
    - In Search of Publication Outlets, undated (Folder 20.4)
    - In the Wake of the Printing Press, 1977 (Folder 20.5)
    - In the Wake of the Printing Press, 1977-1988 (Folder 20.6)
    - Is the Printing Revolution and 18th Century Construct?, undated (Folder 20.7)
    - Les Libraires et les Lumieres, 1981 (Folder 71.3)
    - Les Libraires et les Lumieres, 1982 (Folder 20.8)
    - Les Libraires et les Lumieres, 1996 (Folder 20.9)
    - Lyell Lectures, 1990-1991; [unused illustrations] (Folder 20.10)
    - MIT "Reviws" talk, 1979 (Folder 71.4)
    - The Neglected Media Revolution, 1988 (Folder 20.11)
    - Nineteenth Century Reactions, Twentieth Century Discontents, between 1993 and 2001 (Folder 20.12)
    - Oberlin lectures, 1979-1995 (Folder 20.13)
    - Old Media in the New Millennium, 1999 (Folder 20.14)
    - Old Media in the New Millennium, 2000 (Folder 21.1)
    - Old Media in the New Millennium, 2002 (Folder 21.2)
    - On the Fate of the Printed Word, 1996 (Folder 21.3)
    - The Persistence of the Past, 1993 (Folder 21.4)
    - Perspectives on Media Change, undated (Folder 21.5)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, 1980 (Folder 21.6)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, 1981 (Folder 21.7)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, circa 1980-1981 (Folders 21.8-10)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, 1985 (Folder 21.11)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, circa 1985 (Folder 21.12)
    - Print Culture and Enlightenment Thought, 1986 (Folder 21.13)
    - The Printed Word as a Mode of Political Action, undated (Folder 21.14)
    - Printing and the Permanent Renaissance, 1973 (Folder 71.3)
    - Printing and the Permanent Renaissance, 1974 (Folder 22.1)
    - Printing and the Permanent Renaissance, 1983 (Folder 22.2)
    - Printing as a Divine Art, 1994 (Folder 22.3)
    - Printing as a Divine Art, 1994-1995 (Folder 22.4)
    - Printing as a Divine Art, 1994-1995; [illustrations] (Folder 22.5)
    - Printing as a Divine Art, 1995 (Folder 22.6)
    - Printing as a Divine Art, 2004 (Folder 22.7)
    - Proclaiming the End of the Book, circa 1995 (Folder 22.8)
    - Proclaiming the End of the Book, 2001 (Folder 22.9)
    - The Publicist as Demagogue, circa 1988 (Folder 22.10)
    - The Publicist as Demagogue, 1988-1992 (Folder 22.11)
    - The Publicist in Politics, undated (Folder 23.1)
    - Rare book talk, 2007 (Folder 23.2)
    - Reactions to a New Medium in the Old Millennium, 2013 (Folder 23.3)
    - Remarks at the Evelyn Clark Memorial Service, 2001 (Folder 23.4)
    - The Role of Publication and the Rise of Modern Science, 1974 (Folder 23.5)
    - Rosenbach lectures, circa 2009-2010 (Folder 23.6)
    - Seeing Images/Hearing Texts, 2008 (Folder 23.7)
    - Some Early Encounters with the Printed Text, 1997 (Folder 23.8)
    - Some Perspectives on Media Change, 1996 (Folder 23.9)
    - Some Political Uses of Print, 1987 (Folder 23.10)
    - St. Albans School lecture, 1985 (Folder 23.11)
    - The Two-Faced Printer, 2004 (Folder 23.12)
    - The Two-Faced Printer, undated (Folder 23.13)
    - The Two-Faced Printer, undated; [illustrations] (Folder 23.14)
    - Vassar College talks, 1968, 1977 (Folder 23.15)
    - When Our Old Medium Was New, 2014 (Folder 23.16)
    - The World of Prosper Marchand, 1988-1989 (Folder 23.17)
    - The World of Prosper Marchand, circa 1989 (Folder 24.1)
    - The World of Prosper Marchand, 1989-1991 (Folder 24.2)
    - The World of Prosper Marchand, 1990-1991 (Folder 24.3)
    - Miscellaneous lecture drafts, 1993-2007 (Folder 24.4)
  - Memoir
    - Memoir, circa 2010-2015 (Folders 24.5-8)
    - Memoir, circa 2010-2015 (Folders 25.1-5)
  - Miscellaneous Writings
    - [Comments by] Elizabeth Eisenstein, undated (Folder 25.6)
    - Journalism and French Politics, undated (Folder 25.7)
    - Politics as Vocation, undated (Folder 25.8)
    - Rebuttal to Robert Darnton, 1990 (Folder 25.9)
    - Unidentified typescript with notes, undated (Folder 25.10)
    - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Folder 25.11)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, circa 1960-circa 1975 (Folder 71.6)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated; [Conspiracy-Bourgeois Bohemia/French Revolution] (Folder 71.7)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated; [Impact of printing] (Folder 71.8)
- SERIES III. CONFERNENCE MATERIALS
  - The 18th Century in the Year 2000, 1998 (Folder 25.12)
  - A.A.V.C. Centennial, 1971 (Folder 25.13)
  - Agent of Change: the Current State of Print Culture Studies, 2007 (Folder 25.14)
  - American Antiquarian Society-Seminar on the History of the Book in American, 1980-1986; [Printing and Society in Early America/Needs and Opportunities Conference] (Folders 26.1-2)
  - American Antiquarian Society-Seminar on the History of the Book in American, 1984-1985; [Needs and Opportunities Conference] (Folder 26.3)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1963 (Folder 71.9)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1971 (Folder 26.4)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1974-1987 (Folder 26.5)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1984 (Folders 26.6-7)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1987 (Folder 26.8)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1989 (Folder 27.1)
  - American Historical Association Annual Meeting, 1997 (Folder 27.2)
  - American Historical Association - International Committee for the Historical Sciences, 1990 Congress, 1987; [roundtable proposal] (Folder 27.3)
  - American Printing History Association Annual Meeting, 1979-1980 (Folder 27.4)
  - American Printing History Association Annual Meeting, 1979-1981 (Folder 27.5)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies Annual Meeting, 1977 (Folder 27.6)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies Annual Meeting, 1984 (Folder 27.7)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies Annual Meeting, 1989 (Folder 27.8)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies Annual Meeting, 2001 (Folder 27.9)
  - American Society of Church History Conference, 1980 (Folder 27.10)
  - Baltimore-Washington Old Regime Group, 1996 (Folder 27.11)
  - Baltimore-Washington Old Regime Group, 2005 (Folder 27.12)
  - The Bible as Book, 1996 (Folder 28.1)
  - The Bible as Book, 1999 (Folder 28.2)
  - The Bicentennial of the French Revolution: a Symposium, 1987-1989 (Folder 28.3)
  - The Book on the Islamic World, 1989-1997 (Folder 28.4)
  - The Book on the Islamic World, 1990 (Folders 28.5-6)
  - The Book: Past, Present and Future, 1997-1998 (Folder 28.7)
  - Books and Society in History, 1978-1980 (Folder 28.8)
  - Books and Society in History, circa 1980 (Folder 28.9)
  - Books and Society in History, 1980-1981 (Folder 28.10)
  - British Political Thought in an Age of Globalization, c. 1750-1800, 2008 (Folder 28.11)
  - British Political Thought in Early Modern Europe, 2000 (Folder 28.12)
  - Canadian Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies: Revolutions and Reactions/Revolutions et reactions, 1990 (Folder 29.1)
  - Clark Library Symposium, 1988 (Folders 29.2-3)
  - The Concept of Liberty, 1986 (Folder 29.4)
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe, 1750-1850, 1974-1987 (Folder 29.5)
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe, 1750-1850: Eighth Annual Meeting, 1978 (Folder 29.6)
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe, 1750-1850: Eleventh Annual Meeting, 1980-1981 (Folder 29.7)
  - Consortium on Revolutionary Europe, 1750-1850: Thirty-Seventh Annual Meeting, 2007 (Folders 29.8-9)
  - Cultural Transmission in Medieval and Renaissance Europe, 1987-1988 (Folder 29.10)
  - Cultural Transmission in Medieval and Renaissance Europe, 1988 (Folder 29.11)
  - Cultural Transmission in Medieval and Renaissance Europe, 1988 (Folders 30.1-2)
  - Culture et Revolution, 1987-1988 (Folder 30.3)
  - Defining Authenticity in the Digital Environment, 2000 (Folder 30.4)
  - The Early Modern Book Colloquium, 1994 (Folder 30.5)
  - The European Conscience, 1973 (Folder 30.6)
  - Evalyn A. Clark Symposium, 1993 (Folder 30.7)
  - Evening Dialogue - Woodrow Wilson Center, 1976 (Folder 30.8)
  - Fifteenth International Congress on Medieval Studies, 1980 (Folder 30.9)
  - First Images of America, 1975 (Folder 30.10)
  - Folger Institute Seminars, 1986-1987 (Folders 31.1-4)
  - Folger Institute Seminars, 1986-1988 (Folders 31.5-6)
  - Freedom Forum Seminar, 1995 (Folder 31.7)
  - Further Transactions of the Book, 2006 (Folder 31.8)
  - Les Gazettes Europeanes de langue Francaise (17e-18e siecles), 1992 (Folder 32.1)
  - Global Print Seminar, 2008-2011 (Folder 32.2)
  - The Global Ramifications of the French Revolution, 1989 (Folder 32.3)
  - De Gutenberg ao Tercio Milenio, 1999-2000 (Folder 32.4)
  - History of Libraries and Culture in America, 1995 (Folder 32.5)
  - History of the Book: the Next Generation, 2000 (Folder 32.6)
  - The Impact of Printing 1450-1550, 1992 (Folder 32.7)
  - Information, Power and Media through the Ages, 1999 (Folder 32.8)
  - Institute d'Histoire et de Civilisation Francaises, 1986-1988 (Folder 32.9)
  - Intellectual History and the History of the Book, 2004 (Folder 32.10)
  - International Congress on the History of the French Revolution, 1988-1989 (Folder 33.1)
  - International Summit of the Book, 2012 (Folder 33.2)
  - John Locke and the Political Thought of the 1680s, 1980 (Folder 33.3)
  - Legacy of George Mason, 1988 (Folder 33.4)
  - Leiden Seminar, 1984 (Folder 33.5)
  - Literacy and Social Change, 1981-1982 (Folder 33.6)
  - Literacy, Education and Society in Post-Reformation Europe in Light of Swedish Sources, 1980 (Folders 33.7-9)
  - Literacy in Historical Perspective, 1980 (Folder 33.10)
  - Literacy in Historical Perspective, 1980 (Folder 34.1-2)
  - Le livre dans les societes pre-industrielles, 1981-1982 (Folder 34.3)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon and Vassar Traditions, 1985 (Folder 34.4)
  - The Making of the Public Mind, 1979 (Folders 34.5-6)
  - Margaret Aston Festschrift Conference, 2008 (Folder 34.7)
  - Media Ecology Association Annual Convention, 2002 (Folder 34.8)
  - The Nature and Consequences of Literacy, 1981 (Folder 34.9)
  - New Paradigms and Parallels: the Printing Press as and the Internet, 2000 (Folders 34.10-12)
  - Ninth Conference on Medieval Studies, 1974 (Folder 35.1)
  - Past and Present Annual Conference, 1979 (Folder 35.2)
  - Patronage in Renaissance Europe, 1977 (Folder 35.3)
  - Perspectives on Political Reporting, 1993 (Folder 35.4)
  - Printing and Society in America, 1640-1860, 1980 (Folders 35.5-6)
  - La presse devant la Revolution 1788-1793, 1988 (Folder 71.10)
  - Produzione e commercio della carta e del libro, 1991 (Folder 71.11)
  - Publishing and Readership in Revolutionary France and America, 1989 (Folder 35.7)
  - Renaissance Society of America Annual Meeting, 2011 (Folder 35.8)
  - Republican Patriotism and the French Revolution, 1988 (Folder 35.9)
  - Reseau international "Histoire du livre, histoire de edition, 1990 (Folder 35.10)
  - Science and Technology Studies, 1980 (Folder 35.11)
  - Senastiana Serlio a Lyon: Architecture and Imprimerie, 1994-1988 (Folder 35.12)
  - Seminar on Enlightenment and Revolution, 1992 (Folder 35.13)
  - Sixteenth-Century Studies Conference, 1970-1974 (Folder 35.14)
  - Sixteenth-Century Studies Conference, 1973-1974 (Folder 36.1)
  - Sixteenth-Century Studies Conference, 1976 (Folder 36.2)
  - Smithsonian Symposium on Copernicus, 1973 (Folder 36.3)
  - Society for French Historical Studies Annual Conference, 1966-1976 (Folder 71.12)
  - Society for French Historical Studies Annual Conference, 1973-1979 (Folder 71.13)
  - Society for French Historical Studies Annual Conference, 1988 (Folder 36.4)
  - Society for French Historical Studies Annual Meeting, 1994 (Folder 36.5)
  - Society for French Historical Studies Annual Meeting, 1997 (Folder 36.6)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing Annual Conference, 1995 (Folders 36.7-8)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing Annual Conference, 2007 (Folder 36.9)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing Annual Conference, 2011 (Folder 36.10)
  - Technology and the Rest of Culture, 1996-1997 (Folder 36.11)
  - Technology of Writing Seminar, 1987 (Folder 36.12)
  - Telematikkseminaret, 1997 (Folder 36.13)
  - Tempe, Arizona, conference, 1985 (Folder 71.14)
  - Transactions of the Book, 2001 (Folder 36.14)
  - University Seminar on Communications and Society, 1984 (Folder 36.15)
  - Violence and the French Revolution, 2001 (Folder 36.16)
  - Voice, Text and Hypertext at the Millennium, 1997 (Folder 36.17)
  - Washington Area Group for Print Culture Studies, 2000-2009 (Folder 36.18)
  - Washington, DC, Library of Congress conference, circa 2010 (Folder 37.1)
  - Washington Renaissance Seminar, 1972 (Folder 37.2)
  - Western Society for 18th Century Studies, 1993 (Folders 37.3-4)
  - What is a Scientific Author? Cultures of Scientific Printing, 2013 (Folder 37.5)
  - Work in Progress Seminars, 1987-1988 (Folder 37.6)
- SERIES IV. PUBLISHING FILES
  - Contracts, royalty statements - Cambridge University Press, 1980-2007 (Folder 37.7)
  - Contracts, royalty statements - Cambridge University Press, 1983-1984 (Folder 73.4)
  - Publicity materials - Cambridge University Press, undated (Folder 37.8)
  - Royalty statements - Authors' Registry/ALCS; Cambridge University Press; Oxford University Press, 1993-2011 (Folder 37.9)
  - Royalty statements - Cambridge University Press, 1980-2007 (Folder 73.5)
  - Royalty statements - Cambridge University Press, 1993-2013 (Folders 37.10-11)
  - Royalty statements - Cambridge University Press, Unione Tipografico- Editrice Torinese, 1983-1990 (Folder 73.6)
  - Royalty statements - Oxford University Press, 2000-2002 (Folder 37.12)
- SERIES V. PROFESSIONAL FILES
  - American University. Department of History, 1967-1974 (Folder 37.13)
  - Annual reports, 1980-1986 (Folder 37.14)
  - Biographical sketches, 1995-2001 (Folder 38.1)
  - Biographical sketches, curriculum vitae, circa 1976-circa 1993 (Folder 38.2)
  - Biographical sketches, curriculum vitae, circa 1981-1987 (Folder 38.3)
  - Biographical sketches, curriculum vitae, 2004-2010 (Folder 38.4)
  - Biographical sketches, curriculum vitae, transcripts, 1952-1988 (Folder 38.5)
  - Curriculum vitae, circa 1991-1993 (Folder 38.6)
  - Curriculum vitae, circa 1993 (Folder 38.7)
  - Curriculum vitae, circa 2015 (Folder 38.8)
  - Job applications/offers, 1956-1977 (Folder 38.9)
  - Publication lists, circa 1974-circa 1987 (Folder 38.10)
  - University of Michigan. Department of History, 1982-2003 (Folder 38.11)
- SERIES VI. AWARDS AND HONORS
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Fellowship, 1981 (Folder 38.12)
  - American Historical Association Award for Scholarly Distinction, 2002-2003 (Folder 38.13)
  - Guggenheim Foundation Fellowship, 1981-1983 (Folder 38.14)
  - Gutenberg Award, 2012 (Folder 38.15)
  - Gutenberg Award, 2012-2013 (Folder 72.1)
  - Media Ecology Association Walter Ong Award, 2005 (Folder 38.16)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Ralph Waldo Emerson Award, 1979 (Folder 38.17)
  - University of Michigan Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, 2004 (Folder 38.18)
- SERIES VII. TEACHING MATERIALS
  - American University, circa 1967 (Folder 39.1)
  - American University, 2012 (Folders 39.2-8)
  - American University, undated (Folders 39.9-10)
  - American University, undated (Folder 72.2)
  - [American University?], circa 2012 (Folder 39.11)
  - American University/University of Michigan, 1970-circa 1980 (Folder 39.12)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1973 (Folder 72.3)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1999 (Folders 39.13-15)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1999 (Folders 40.1-4)
  - Stanford University, 1981 (Folder 40.5)
  - A (Folder 40.6)